CURRICULUM VITAE

RICHARD VAN NAIRN

PROFILE

An ambitious, enthusiastic individual who has shown dedication throughout his whole life. This is demonstrated through the possession of first class bachelors and masters degrees. Richard has developed and polished his ability to sell any product to consumers of any background. After 4 successful years at LMC Audio and 2 years as UK Account Manager at Martin Audio with an additional year as EMEA Account Manager, Richard has acquired the necessary skills to be an asset to the sales division of any company in a variety of fields.

EDUCATION

University of West London, Ealing, (2009-2010)

· MA Recording Productions- Distinction (1:1)

University of West London, Ealing, (2006-2009)

BA Honours Degree- Music Technology (1:1)

Esher College, Thames Ditton, (2004-2006)

· Music A/S Level · Design Technology A- Level · Media A- Level

WORK EXPERIENCE & PREVIOUS EMPLOYMENT

2019 to present: Martin Audio EMEA Account Manager

- Actively develop the brand within key territories, look for new avenues to market.
- Continue to provide distributors the skills and resources necessary to complete not only their long and short term goals and targets, but aid their customers in achieving their own goals as well.
- Travel to EMEA territories, take in their culture and learn what it takes for them to succeed.
- Work with EMEA team to increase EMEA overall turnover in a short space of time.
- Developed upon existing team work and communication skills.

2017 to 2019: Martin Audio UK and EMEA Account Manager

- Actively develop the brand within key territories in order to steal market share of competing brands
- Collaborate with distributors to push into untapped market places. Provide the necessary skills and resources to achieve their long and short term goals and targets.
- Travel the UK, support customers and their end client.
- Be a beacon for the brand Martin Audio.
- Developed upon existing team work and communication skills.

2015 to 2017: Martin Audio – UK Account Manager

- Actively develop new customer relationships.
- Capitalize on brand strength to push into new territories and income streams.
- Travelled the UK to meet with potential and existing clients face to face.

- Considerably increased overall UK growth in a short space of time.
- · Developed upon existing team work and communication skills

2011- 2015: LMC Audio Systems- London

- Developed leads and executed deals through telephone and face to face client meetings
- Attended trade shows resulting in building strong client relationships.
- Exceeded expectations by striving to meet and surpass sales targets outlined on a quarterly basis.

SKILLS

- Fully proficient in Data and IT infrastructure packages including Oracle and SAP.
- Fully proficient in graphics packages and Microsoft Office, including Excel and PowerPoint.
- Fully proficient in both Windows and Mac OSX.
- Extensively travelled